I got you some beef noodles.
牛肉面来了
I'm starving.
饿死我了
Here you go.
给你
There's so little beef here.
这牛肉也太少了一点吧
Look how round your face is.
你脸都圆成什么样了
Eat less, girl.
你少吃点吧 少女
Your pinch stretched my face, okay?
我的脸是被你捏的好吧
Stingy.
真抠门
I work so hard but all I get is a bowl of vegetable noodles.
让我干活 还让我吃素面
I'm here.
我来了
The noodles smell so good.
面这么香
Are you having beef noodles for today?
今天吃牛肉面啊
Xue Wanwan?
薛晚晚
What are you doing here?
你怎么来了
You didn't see me, huh?
敢情你刚才都没看见我
I don't see you.
我看不见你
All I see is her.
我眼里只有她
Other people do not exist.
其他人对我来说都是空气
Dao Ruifeng, are you sick of living?
刀锐锋 你是不是找死
What?
你干吗
I suggest you to be nice.
我劝你善良
Your brother has announced
你哥已经官宣了
that he'll once again be my investor.
打算再给我当一回投资人
You don't know?
你不知道
Her brother was your investor before?
她哥还给你投过资
He's so nice to you.
对你这么好呢
Her brother treats me very nicely.
她哥不要对我太好了
Right? Xue Wanwan.
对吧 薛晚晚
My first bucket of gold
我人生的第一桶金
was all thanks to her brother.
就是她哥给的
I experienced the fun of making money.
我也算体验了一把赚钱的乐趣
Right, Xue Wanwan?
对吧 薛晚晚
It looks like there's an inside story.
看来有内情啊
There's nothing between us.
没什么内情
In freshman year, my brother hit him.
大一的时候 我哥把他打了
He suffered a mild concussion. So he compensated him more than 500,000 yuan.
轻微脑震荡 赔了五十多万呢
500,000? So much?
五十多万 这么多
500,000 isn't much at all.
五十多万还叫多
My grandmother gave me all the money.
我奶奶当时把钱全给我了
I spent a little bit of money
我就拿了一点小钱
on a crappy computer to write web novels.
买了一个破电脑写网文
As for the rest of the 400,000 yuan,
剩下四十多万
I spent it on fake view numbers.
我全部用来刷榜了
And somehow,
一不小心
I became a Top-10 writer.
就成了年度十佳作家之一
Don't worry,
你放心啊
the orthopedics department of our hospital is first-class,
咱们医院的骨科那是一流的
I'll help you call them later.
我一会儿就给你联系
Seriously?
真的
I guarantee that during your stay here,
我保证在住院期间
you'll be able to write in peace.
一定能够安心写作
Thank you, Doctor Cheng.
谢谢程医生
All I want is to be with you.
我就想和你在一起
I'm very thoughtful.
我就是这么贴心
If you become disabled,
你要是残疾了
I'll offer myself to you to offset my brother's sin.
我就以身相许 替我哥赎罪
It's best that you sit in a wheelchair
最好你以后就坐轮椅
so that you don't go around flirting with girls.
省得你到处招蜂引蝶
I'll get the best wheelchair for you.
我给你买最好的轮椅
Let me go.
你把手给我撒开
Qian Cheng said he'd buy me an electric chair.
钱程说给我买电动的
I can buy one, too.
我也可以买
Speaking of Qian Cheng,
说起钱程
how is he doing lately?
他最近怎么样了
He's doing well.
他挺好的
He had a dream in the office.
刚在那个办公室做春梦呢
Having a dream?
做梦
He is starting to have dreams?
他开始做梦了
You need to contact his doctor right away.
那你赶紧联系他的主治医生
He needs psychological counseling.
他需要做心理疏导
Once a patient starts to have dreams,
病人一旦开始做梦
their emotions may get unstable.
说明情绪容易波动
They'll have a mental breakdown.
是很容易发病的
Listen to me.
你听我说呀
No counseling is needed.
不用疏导
I've been doing this for ten years
我已经疏导他十年了
and it has been futile.
没什么用
I tell you what,
我告诉你
during a therapy,
心理治疗中
the most important thing
最重要的过程呢
is the patient's own words.
就是病人的自述
If he can't express himself well
如果他没有办法好好地表达自己
or he's hiding something,
或者有所隐瞒的话
the therapy shall stagnate.
那么治疗就会停滞
Stagnate?
停滞
Dao Ruifeng!
刀锐锋
Let him stagnate, then.
你让他停滞吧
Dao Ruifeng, you're unbelievable.
刀锐锋 我真是服了你了
Can you stop avoiding the topic?
你能不能不要顾左右而言他啊
I tell you what,
我告诉你
if you treat him as your best friend,
你如果把他当兄弟的话
you should help him get better.
你就要帮他好好治疗
Do not try to hide his problems, okay?
而不是只帮他隐瞒知道吗
If this continues,
如果一直这样隐瞒下去
he'll only become sicker.
他的病情只会越来越严重
Okay.
我知道了
Stop eating.
不许吃了
Eat mine.
你吃我的
I don't want yours.
我不想吃你的
I only want hers.
我只想吃她的
Eat it!
你吃
No.
不吃
Sorry.
不好意思
Sorry to keep you waiting.
让你久等了
It's fine.
没事
I came to ask you a question.
我就是过来问一下
I heard there was a problem with Bella's body?
听说贝拉的遗体也出问题了
Drive me to Qing'ai Building.
送我去青霭大厦吧
I'll give you the details in the car.
路上详细跟你说
Let's go.
走
You mean
你是说
there was only a little cyanosis
这回贝拉身上的紫绀
on Bella's body,
非常轻微
and there was no sign of hair lost?
而且遗体没有了脱发的迹象
Any thoughts?
你有什么想法吗
There isn't much time for the police.
看来留给警方的时间不多了
In terms of the research of a medication,
一般研制药品
the potency and side effects are the two important indicators.
看的就是药物的药效和副作用
If the side effect is
如果贝拉身上的副作用
so small on Bella,
变得这么小的话
it means the research of the medication
那证明这个药
is about to succeed.
也许快要研制成功了
Succeed?
研制成功
Why did Mrs. Xu and Bella both die?
那为什么徐奶奶跟贝拉都死了
They should've been cured, right?
吃完不是应该痊愈吗
It isn't an elixir.
这药又不是仙丹
One bite won't cure you.
吃一口就能好
Putting aside the fact that leukemia, cancer,
且不说这白血病 癌症
and other incurable diseases
都是一些绝症
need adjuvant treatment,
都需要辅助治疗
as far as we know,
而且据咱们现在所知
all the pill-takers
现在的服药人
came by it accidentally.
全都是偶然接触到药品
Only part of the effect is reached,
只能达到部分疗效
so I think there must be a long-term pill-taker
所以我觉得在这个制药者的身边
around the pill-maker.
一定有一个长期的服药者
Unlike the experimental subjects
而不是像徐奶奶和贝拉
like Mrs. Xu and Bella,
这种试验者
the person is a real participant of the project.
而是这个项目真正的参与者
And this person
而且这个人
may have been cured.
现在已经痊愈了也说不定
You're right.
你说得对
No accurate information could be gained
光凭外面这些药物试验
from these non-consistent drug tests outside.
根本得不到什么准确信息
Xiaoyu,
小鱼
do you see the car behind us?
你看见后面那辆车了吗
What?
怎么了
I think it's been following us
好像从殡仪馆出来之后
since we left the funeral home.
就一直跟着咱们
Really? What do we do?
真的 那怎么办
Sit tight.
你坐好了
I'll try another way.
我换条路试试看
It doesn't feel right, Xiaoyu.
不太对劲啊 小鱼
Call the police.
报警吧
Okay.
好
No, it'd be too late.
不行 来不及了
Look, Xiaoyu.
这样 小鱼
I'll find a chance to slow down,
我一会儿找机会减速
and you jump off the car.
你跳下去
No, let's jump together!
不行 我们一起跳车
Don't be absurd, Xiaoyu.
别逗了 小鱼
There's nothing out there.
这外边什么都没有
Where do we hide after we jump?
咱们跳下去躲哪儿啊
You get off first.
你先下去
No.
不行
Let's jump together.
要跳一起跳
Quickly!
快
Lin Nuoyan!
林诺言
Xiaoyu,
小鱼
I'll be fine.
我不会有事的
There's a crossroads ahead.
就在前面那个路口
Jump after I count down from 3.
我数三二一 你就跳
You hear me?
听见了吗
Get ready.
准备
Three.
三
Two.
二
One!
一
Jump!
跳
Hello?
喂
We were going downtown from the municipal funeral home.
我们在市内殡仪馆回城的路上
A car just hit us.
刚刚有车撞我们
Come help us.
快来救我们
Lin Nuoyan!
林诺言
How's Professor Lin?
林教授怎么样了
I don't know.
我不知道
He was just sent to the emergency room.
刚送进去抢救了
It might be the person who hit Officer Su.
可能就是撞苏警官的人
He chased after us in a car.
他开汽车追我们
It's okay.
没事了
- It's okay. - It's alright now.
没事了 已经没事了
Lin Nuoyan will be fine.
林诺言不会有事的
Lin Nuoyan.
林诺言
Thank you for saving my girlfriend.
谢谢你救我女朋友
- Thank you. - What are you doing?
谢谢谢谢 你干吗
Thank you for saving my girlfriend.
谢谢你救了我女朋友
I'm so grateful for you.
感谢
Don't think too much.
别想太多了
I only wanted to save her.
我就是想救她而已
Xiaoyu,
小鱼
your hand is injured.
你的手受伤了
- He has a mild concussion. - Your hand.
轻微脑震荡 这个手
His arm is dislocated
胳膊脱臼了
and his ankle is sprained.
脚踝扭伤了
The rest are just scratches.
剩下的都是擦伤
He needs to stay the night for observation.
今天晚上需要住院观察
Who is his family?
你们谁是家属
Allow me.
我来
I'll cover all of his medical costs.
他一切费用我来承担
I'm okay.
没事
I just feel a bit...
就是有点
I'm a bit dizzy.
有点头晕
I'm glad that you're okay.
你没事就好了
Does it still hurt?
还疼吗
So?
怎么样
Are your girlfriend
你女朋友
and her boyfriend okay?
跟她的男朋友还好吗
According to typical storylines,
按照正常逻辑
shouldn't the supporting role who has unrequited love
暗恋女主的男二号骑士
for the heroine sacrifice himself?
不是得祭天的吗
The writer for our show
咱们这戏的编剧老师
is not professional enough.
太不敬业了
You're really something else.
厉害啊
He saved your girlfriend,
人家救了你女朋友
and this is how you see him?
你怎么可以这个样子
It's good that he isn't dead.
不死也好
Otherwise, there would be another innocent victim.
否则又得伤及一个无辜的人
But still, I need to thank you
不过 还是得感谢你
for making me travel all the way here
让我大老远跑过来
to watch a good show.
看一出好戏啊
I didn't ask you to come here to watch a show.
我叫你来 不是让你来看戏的
Do my favor.
帮我个忙啊
The perpetrator failed at the first attempt,
这个凶手 第一次没有得逞
so he'll definitely try again.
他肯定还有下一次
Even if he doesn't,
就算没有下一次的话
he'll be watching our moves.
最近肯定也会观察我们的动向
Help me get two men
帮我找两个人
to protect Lin Nuoyan in secret
暗中保护林诺言
and to see if anyone's following him.
看看他身边有没有盯梢的
Okay.
好
Get two men
安排两个人
to see if there's anyone suspicious
看看林教授周边
around Professor Lin.
有什么可疑之人
I think
我感觉啊
the murderer can't
这个凶手应该是
wait to show himself.
忍不住要浮出水面了
Why did you ask me to go kart racing with you?
你怎么想到叫我玩这个
It crossed my mind so I called you.
想到就叫你了
That's it?
就这
See what I'd like to see.
想见什么就去见
Do what I'd like to do.
想做什么就去做
Simple as that.
就这么简单
If I don't do it now,
这一秒不去做的话
no one knows
下一秒会发生什么
what will happen in the next second.
谁也不知道
No one knows
我们会分开多久
You're a bit different from before.
你跟以前有点不太一样了
What was I like before?
我以前什么样啊
You would ask boys to help you open bottles.
都是男孩子帮你拧瓶盖
Was I that spoiled?
我有那么矫情吗
(City Tournament) No.
不
You were like a goddess.
你是女神
Every time we had a match,
每次比赛
when watching you cheering for us,
看你给我们加油跳操
I'd really want to get you a bottle of water.
我都很想给你拿水
But William was too nasty.
但是William太贱了
If he had known that I liked you,
他要是知道我喜欢你
he would have pursued you.
肯定跑去追你
That's why I didn't express my feelings.
所以我也没敢表现出来
William knew you liked me a long time ago.
William早就知道你喜欢我
Everybody knew.
全校人都知道
I knew, too.
我也知道
You were the only one
只是你呀
who didn't know that everybody knew.
不知道此事已经天下皆知
Who told everyone else?
是谁说出去的
Duh!
这还用说吗
You basically wrote "I like Ye Lai"
你都已经把我喜欢叶莱
on your face.
刻在脑门上了
Many told me
好多人跟我说
that Qian Cheng, the captain of the basket team, liked me.
篮球队的队长钱程喜欢你
So I waited for you to approach me.
我就等你来啊
(Welcome to race club) I waited and waited,
可我左等右等
but you never did.
你都没有来
So I started to doubt myself.
我就怀疑
Was I feeling too good about myself
是不是我自作多情
or were they blind?
还是他们眼瞎
I would have confessed to you if I had known.
早知道我就去跟你说了
I'll go home and beat the hell out of William.
回去我就锤死William
If William had been cheeky,
William如果是真贱的话
he would have pursued me a long time ago.
他早就来追我了
He did this because he wanted to prod you
他这么做 不过想刺激你
into making a decision.
让你早点做决定罢了
It's so good to be an adult.
长大了真好啊
I can get things
可以把心里的话
off my chest without any worries.
勇敢地说出来
Sorry.
对不起
I was being a coward.
我那会儿太怂了
Are you still a coward now?
那你现在还怂吗
I-It's too sudden.
这 这也太快了
I can't even react.
我有点没反应过来
At the banquet,
那天在宴会上
you were quite brave.
你可是很勇敢的呀
I was too emotional.
那天我太激动了
I had ten years of therapy in the US,
我在美国接受了十年的治疗
I can accept all the miseries that happened to me.
我已经完全能够接受那些不幸了
Over the past decade,
十年来
whenever I felt confused or unbearable,
每当我痛苦 困惑的时候
what you said would cross my mind.
都会想起你跟我说的那句话
Qian Cheng,
钱程
I'm going abroad.
我要出国去了
I may never come back again.
可能再也不会回来了
You must strive to live.
你一定要努力的活下去
What are you talking about?
说什么傻话
You're the one who should strive.
你这样子 才要努力呢
You know what I mean.
你知道我的意思的
In life,
人活着
sorrow, pain, and sadness
悲伤 痛苦 难过了
are all trivial.
都没关系
You must stay alive.
你一定要活下去
I have done it,
我做到了
and I'm striving to live.
也努力地活着
What about you?
你呢
I'm fine.
我很好
I'm healthy.
身体健康
Everything
一切
is fine.
都好
You
你
told the therapist about
把我的那件事
what happened to me?
跟心理医生说了
No.
没有
I never told
那件事
anyone about it.
我谁也没告诉
I didn't even
就连William
tell William.
我也没告诉
Thank you.
谢谢你
At that time, you saved my life
当年不但保护了我的生命
and my reputation.
还保护了我的名誉
I won't stay long
我这次回来
this time.
不会待太久
I just wanted to ask you
我就想问问你
if you're willing to go to the US with me.
愿不愿意跟我一起去美国
I'm seeing a therapist, too.
我也接受了心理治疗
I know
我知道
it's bad for you
不能把完全的把事实说出来
to keep my matters a secret.
会对病情不利的
You kept my secret.
你一直替我保密
You're trading your health
这是拿你的健康
for my new life.
在换取我的新生活
Though we can't be together,
虽然我们没有办法在一起了
I genuinely want the best for you.
但是我是真心为你好
Go to the US with me
你和我去美国吧
to see my therapist.
去见我的心理医生
He's really good.
他真的很好的
You can share everything with him.
你可以把一切都告诉他
To leave this place...
离开这里
The moment I got my proof of health,
我拿到康复证明的第一刻
I came back to see you.
就是回国来见你
Please think about
我的提议
my proposal.
你考虑一下
Cheng,
小程
help me perform extraction separation
帮我把这个贝拉的头发
on Bella's hair.
进行一下萃取分离吧
Okay.
好
Young Master,
少爷
I'll help you.
我来帮你
What's the matter with Cheng?
这小程是怎么了
He's like a mediating monk.
跟个老僧入定一样
How can a monk meditate for a girl?
老僧怎么会为了一个姑娘入定啊
If Jin Xiaoyu sees him like this,
他这样让金小鱼看见了
God knows what she'll say.
指不定会说什么呢
No one in love
坠入爱河的人
would care about it.
都不会在意这个
Young Master,
少爷
you speak from experience.
你这个完全是经验之谈
It's been ten years.
十年了
Cheng never had puberty.
小程都没有过青春期
He never had a relationship.
从来没谈过恋爱
It's the first time I see him like this.
这第一次见他这样
This is quite new.
还挺有新鲜感的
You know what Cheng Weilan said?
你知道程蔚蓝怎么说吗
She asked me to take him to a therapist.
程蔚蓝让我带他去看心理医生
This is necessary.
很有这个必要
Is it?
是吗
Qian Tu.
钱途
Hello?
喂
Tu.
小途途
You got something already?
这么快就有消息了
I found Zhao Shan.
赵山找到了
You found him?
找到了
Okay.
好 我知道了
Your brother is here.
你哥来了
I need to see Qian Tu.
我跟钱途还有点事
Look after him.
管好咱们家大程子
You got it, Young Master.
好嘞 少爷
Cheng.
大肠杆菌
So?
怎么说
I've sent my men there.
我已经派人过去了
I hope they'd get him.
希望可以堵到人吧
Are you sure it's Zhao Shan?
你确定是那个赵山
The bodyguard watched Lin Nuoyan for days,
保镖盯了林诺言几天了
and it had been quiet.
一点动静都没有
Today is the first time he's working after getting discharged.
今天是他出院的第一天工作日
A delivery man walked into his lab.
有一个送快递的进过他的实验室
When the delivery man came out, instead of a delivery scooter,
出来之后呢 却没有快递车
he got into a car.
反而上了一辆轿车
The bodyguard cross-checked the photo on the arrest warrant,
保镖对比了通缉令上的照片
and found out that
发现那个人哪
he was Zhao Shan.
他就是赵山
You never let me down.
你从来没让人失望过
This is the place.
就这个地方了
Wait.
不是
What are you doing here?
你们俩在这儿干吗
Where is he?
人呢
Sorry, sir.
对不起 钱总
We were late.
我们慢了一步
When we got here, the door was open
来的时候门开的
but no one was in.
但是没人
This place
这个地方啊
is a temporary den
就是个临时落脚点
to trick you idiots.
专门忽悠你们这帮青瓜蛋子
Let's go in and have a look.
进去看看吧
Let's go.
走
There's a pair of slippers here.
这儿还有双拖鞋呀
This place does look like a temporary shelter.
这地方果然是个临时落脚点
Jiang Baiju,
蒋白驹
it appears that he wasn't after Jin Xiaoyu
这个人之前好像找的不是金小鱼
but Professor Lin.
而是这个林教授
Look.
你看
Jin Xiaoyu's photos
金小鱼的照片
were taken recently.
只是最近才拍的
The older photos are those of Professor Lin.
之前很多都是林教授的单人
Xiaoyu has no parents.
小鱼没有父母
That's why when I started to investigate her,
所以我之前查她的时候
I got nothing.
也是一片空白
And recently, she moved into Buwenzhong.
再加上最近住进了不闻钟
So she basically disappeared from the world.
基本就是个隐形人了
I investigated Professor Lin, too.
这个林教授我也调查过
His parents died
他的父母在他很早的时候
when he was young.
就已经过世了
His adoptive parents took him to the US
他的养父母在他十岁的时候
when he was ten years old.
把他带到了美国
In the US, he studied
他在美国读的是
(Clinical Microbiology Test) genetics and bio-economics.
遗传学和生物经济学
He got good grades.
是个学霸
And
而且
he's into charity.
还热衷于做慈善事业
His adoptive parents retired
他的养父母现在好像是在华盛顿
from a university in Washington.
大学的退休老师
Really?
这么厉害
If one's too perfect,
人太完美
he's unlucky.
就是会倒霉的
You're jealous.
嫉妒
Professor Lin
这个林教授
is a good-looking and highly-educated
长得挺帅 是个学霸
charity-enthusiast.
还热衷于慈善事业
Jin Xiaoyu...
这个金小鱼啊
I don't get it.
我就想不通了
She chose you
不选这个人
over this guy.
选你
It proves one thing, you know?
这说明了一件事你知道吗
Women have
女人的眼光
poor tastes.
不太好看
The older, the more charming.
人越老越有味道
I pity you.
真是同情你
A young man
年纪小
who knows so little.
什么也不懂
Old man,
你这么大岁数了
your roasting ability
吐槽功力
has never improved.
还这样
He seemed like a decent guy
这家伙年轻的时候
when he was young.
还挺人模狗样的啊
There was an accident
这家医院
at this hospital, right?
不是当时出事的那家吗
The Third Affiliated Hospital of Central Hospital.
中央医大下属的第三分院
Their main work was medical research.
当时是做医学研究产业用的
But there was an unexpected major accident.
后来没想到出了这么大的事故
These flowers.
这些花
I've been trying to find them for 80 years.
这些是我找了八十年的花
I'll never forget
那个场景
what I saw.
我这辈子都不会忘
We need to find this place.
我们得找到这个地方
What took you so long?
你怎么才回来呀
Why are you at home?
你怎么会在家
Come.
来
Good boy. Come.
乖 走
How come you came home so late?
你怎么才回来
You...
你
I'll have lunch at home.
我今天在家里吃饭
I'll sleep at home tonight.
晚上住在家里
This doesn't sound right.
不对呀
It's not what you usually do.
很反常
Be honest with me.
老实交代
Are you dating Ye Lai?
是不是跟叶莱再续前缘了
You're too direct.
你这也太直接了
Can you be circumbendibus?
你能不能委婉点
Dad would
你看看爸
talk to me about the dog
都会先跟我聊聊狗
and ask me if I want to keep a pet.
再问问我想不想养宠物
I said no.
我说不想养
Then he suspects that I have a girlfriend.
他就推测我有女朋友了
I see.
这样啊
Do you want to keep a cat?
想养猫吗
No.
不想
What's happening between you and Ye Lai?
你跟叶莱到底怎么了
She asked me to go to an archery club.
她约我去射剑馆
Go-kart a few days ago,
前两天开车
and archery club now?
后两天射剑馆
It's quite obvious.
很明显
Don't you mind?
你不介意吗
She's your girlfriend.
她是你女朋友
Why would I mind?
轮不到我来介意
I know what you're worried about.
我知道你担心什么
You're worried that Mom and Dad would find out about her past
担心爸妈知道她的遭遇
and would disagree.
会反对
But she was the victim,
但她曾经是受害者
not the perpetrator.
又不是加害者
If you don't mind,
只要你不介意
no one does.
没人会介意的
I don't mind.
我不介意
It's like robbery.
这就好像是被抢劫一样
No one's life would be ruined
没有人因为被抢劫过一次
after getting robbed once.
人生就完了
But to a girl,
但对于一个女孩子来说
damage like this
受到这样的伤害
can ruin her life.
人生就完了
I find it ridiculous.
我觉得很荒谬
Yes.
没错
No one is defective because of the damage they had.
人不会受到伤害而成为瑕疵品
What Dad and Mom really care about
爸妈其实真正在乎的
is you.
是你呀
They don't want you to be hurt.
他们不想让你受到伤害
Dad and Mom are open-minded.
爸妈都是心胸宽广之人
They don't judge a girl
他们不会因为这样的一件事情
because of something like that.
去指责一个女孩子的
I learned something lately.
我最近也了解到一些情况
The Ye family didn't want Ye Lai to return to China,
叶家不想让叶莱回来
but she insisted on coming back to see you.
但是死活她要回来找你
She even had a fight with her family.
还跟大家吵了一架
Now that she's in China,
她回来之后
I bet she'll deal with some stuff left from the past.
应该也会猜到有一些旧事
A girl came back for you
这个女孩子这么的不顾一切
at all costs.
都是为了你
You're a man now.
你现在是个男子汉
You should know
你要清楚
that you should make yourself clear
喜欢和不喜欢
whether you like her or not.
要说清楚的
Tu.
哥
If I'm having a relationship now,
我现在要是也恋爱了
how pressured will you be?
你压力该有多大呀
Darn you.
该死
Get lost!
一边去吧你
Nuonuo.
糯糯
Tu.
哥
What are you doing out here?
你怎么出来了
Why was Nuonuo so noisy?
糯糯怎么这么吵
He's dead.
它死了
Qian Cheng.
钱程哥哥
What's up with all those people?
怎么这么多人
I need to make myself clear.
事先声明
I didn't get them here.
可不是我叫的
It's Xue Zaozao's fault.
都怪薛早早
I asked him to order a private room,
我让他订包厢
but he secretly told Peng Zichun.
他偷偷告诉了彭梓春
Ever since Ye Lai came back,
自从叶莱姐姐回来
Peng Zichun has been making attempts.
彭梓春就贼心不死
My brother has been helping him.
我哥就帮着他兴风作浪
I never liked that playboy.
我怎么也看不上那个花花公子
He's a loser
废柴一个
who acts like a boss.
还牛气哄哄的
Qian Cheng,
钱程
I was going to see Wanwan.
我本来是要找晚晚一起玩的
But I didn't expect there'd be
结果这么多人
so many people.
我也是没想到
It's fine.
没事
You didn't invite them here.
又不是你叫的
What did I tell you?
我刚才说什么来着
Qian Cheng is a boss now.
人家钱程现在是钱总了
He doesn't care how many people there are.
不在乎咱们人多人少
But remember,
但是记住啊
I'll be paying
今天
today.
还是我来请
Alright! Alright!
好 好
It's none of your business.
怎么有你事
Do you have nowhere else to spend your money?
你钱多没地方花了
Qian Cheng,
钱程
you go and get some Whiskey.
你去拿点威士忌
These are for women.
这酒都是女人喝的
No one ever told me
我怎么没听说
these drinks were for women.
这酒是女人喝的
There are too many people here.
这儿人太多了
I'd like to speak to Qian Cheng in private.
我想跟钱程单独聊聊
I never liked Whiskey anyway.
我本来就不爱喝威士忌
If you want to talk about business,
你要是聊聊项目合作
I'm quite interested.
我倒是感兴趣
You and Xue Zaozao
你和薛早早不是
opened up an entertainment company, right?
弄了一个娱乐公司吗
Qing'ai sponsored a program that will be broadcasting online next month.
青霭下个月在网站有个冠名节目
There are so many idols in your company.
你家爱豆那么多
Come and have fun.
过来玩玩吧
About this,
这事儿
you need to talk to Xue Zaozao.
你们得跟薛早早聊
I'm but one of the shareholders.
我就是个股东
You can put your girlfriend in the program.
你可以让你女朋友上节目呀
Qian Cheng can squeeze her in.
让钱程安排一下
I don't have a girlfriend.
我哪有女朋友啊
Don't listen to others' nonsense.
别听他们胡说
What's the name of the one
你们公司那个选秀第一名
who won first place in your company's talent show?
叫什么来着
Zihan.
子涵
Yes.
对
Zichun.
一个梓春
And Zihan.
一个子涵
What a perfect match.
你俩可真配
Wanwan.
晚晚
Let's sing.
我们一起唱歌吧
Sure.
好呀
♪Read me between the lines♪
我的弦外之音
♪My unintended harsh words♪
我的有口无心
♪I'm unwilling to be away from Darling, but I'm even more unwilling to be away from you♪
我离不开Darling更离不开你
Where is Qian Cheng?
钱程哥哥去哪儿了
Why isn't he back yet?
怎么还没回来
Maybe it's too crowded here,
有可能今天人太多
so he went out for some time alone.
他出去躲清静了
Why don't we go and find him?
不如我们去找找他吧
Miss, they are fighting.
大小姐 他们打起来了
They are fighting?
打起来了
Who is fighting whom?
谁打起来了
Your two friends.
就你们刚刚那两个朋友
Go, go, go!
走走走
- Go, go, go! - Go have a look.
走走走 去看看啊
Let's go and have a look.
看一下
Over there!
就在前面
You!
你个王八蛋
What are you doing? Sit down!
你干什么 你坐下
Qian Cheng, are you alright?
钱程哥 你没事吧
Zichun!
梓春
How are you, Zichun?
怎么样 梓春
Qian Cheng.
钱程
You...
你
Are you okay?
你没受伤吧
Don't just stand there!
都别愣着了
Call the ambulance!
打电话 叫救护车呀
Qian Tu,
钱途哥
is this a hospital or a prison?
这是医院还是监狱啊
A special hospital for compulsory medical treatment.
这是用于强制医疗的特殊医院
It's close to a prison.
跟监狱也差不多
If he didn't have psychological illness,
要不是有心理病症
he'd be in prison sooner or later.
不然早晚得进监狱
Peng Zichun
彭梓春呢
was badly injured.
可是重伤
I shouldn't have let Qian Cheng
我当时就不应该答应钱程
go on the date.
出去约会
Cheng Weilan was right.
程蔚蓝说得对
Once one is in love,
这人啊 一谈恋爱
they'll have strong emotional changes.
心理起伏就会比较大
There's no point in saying that now.
说什么都没用了
Let's go.
走吧
Cheng, are you okay?
老钱 你没事吧
Are they giving you enough food?
你吃得饱吗
Are those two fat guys mean to you?
后面这俩胖子有没有欺负你
Sit down.
先坐
Just a temporary detention.
只是暂时性的羁押
He's only showing mild symptoms.
他现在症状是轻状的
I'll talk to the Peng family
到时候我和彭家
some other day.
再好好地协调协调
Are you feeling better?
好点没有
I eat and sleep on time.
按时吃饭 按时睡觉
No work, no worries.
不用工作 不用烦恼
This is like a vacation.
像度假一样
Vacation?
度假个屁
Why would they be watching over you if this was a vacation?
度假后面站俩人啊
Uh...
那个
Cheng, don't worry.
老钱 你放心
I promise we'll get you out of here.
我们俩一定会把你弄出去
Don't worry.
你别担心
Qian Cheng,
钱程
listen to me.
你听我说
You just
你呢 现在
forget about everything
什么都不要想
and get some good rest.
好好休息
I'll try to negotiate
那哥哥到时候会去和彭家协调
with the Peng family
商量
to reach a settlement. Okay?
争取和解 是吧
Yeah.
对对对
I'm Xue Zaozao's friend.
我跟薛早早是哥们
And he's Peng Zichun's friend.
他跟彭梓春是哥们
If we can't figure it out,
我们实在不行
we can ask for his help
找他帮帮忙
and compensate Peng Zichun.
赔他钱
The thing between me and Peng Zichun
我跟彭梓春的事
is different from the thing between you and Xue Zaozao.
跟你和薛早早的事不一样
He did it for his sister
他是为了妹妹
whereas I...
我是为了
I knew that!
我就说
We should have listened to your mother
早都应该听你妈妈的
and forbidden you from dating Ye Lai.
不应该让你跟那个叶莱再续前缘
Can you talk less
你在这种场合的时候
on an occasion like this?
少说点不行吗
They said
他们说了
the psychiatric evaluation will be on next Wednesday.
精神鉴定在下周三
I got it.
明白
I'll speak to Chief Fan
我到时候和樊主任呢
in advance.
再好好沟通沟通
Don't worry.
你放心
The most important thing for you now
你现在最重要的就是
is to rest well.
好好休息
Jiang Baiju, is something on your mind?
蒋白驹你怎么心不在焉的
Is it about Qian Cheng?
你是不是因为钱程
Him?
因为他
This is an obvious trick,
这可是个大坑
and I won't fall for it.
我可不往下跳
I just think
我只是觉得
that Lin Nuoyan being discharged from the hospital
林诺言出院
combined with the problem Cheng is having
还有小程这档子事
seems a little suspicious.
放在一块有点蹊跷
It can't be that simple.
没那么简单
You're unbelievable.
你这个死男人
Qian Cheng
有了钱程
and Lin Nuoyan?
还想林诺言
Can you focus on me?
能不能对我专一一点
How is it possible?
怎么可能
Jiang Baiju.
蒋白驹
Do you believe in
你相不相信
destiny?
命运啊
In 1941, I went home
一九四一年我回到家乡
to reunite with my family.
和家人团聚
I was going to have myself cured,
本来是想治好自己的病
but that war
但是一场战争
took my family away.
带走了我全部的家人
I left my hometown along with Dao Qiang,
我带着刀强离开了家乡
and it was a narrow escape
也是九死一生
before I made it abroad.
才去到了国外
But when I was abroad,
可是在国外
I didn't get the answer I wanted.
我没有找到自己想要的答案
In that period of time,
那段时间啊
I missed my hometown all the time.
我每时每刻都在想着自己的家乡
It doesn't feel good to be homeless.
无家可归的感觉非常不好
But now you have a home.
但是现在你有家了呀
And everything will be fine.
而且一切都会好起来
Right?
对不对
It's okay
就算一切好不起来
even if it doesn't.
也没有事
It's normal for people to come
因为总有人来
and go.
也总有人会走嘛
Everybody has their own path of growth.
每个人都会有不同的成长轨迹
Their outlook on the world
他们对事物的看法
and different attitudes
还有不同的态度
may change their direction of life
在一念之间
at a change of mind.
就可以改变自己生活的方向
So everybody
所以每个人
has their unique ending.
都应该会有不同的结局吧
All right.
好了
Cheer up!
你开心一点嘛
Smile.
笑一个
I'm fine.
我没事
It's just I can't help with these legal affairs.
只是这种法律事务我插不上手
I can only sit around being worried.
只能干着急
Ye Lai
叶莱啊
knew Cheng in high school.
她在高中的时候就和小程认识
They went through adversities,
俩人一起经历了磨难
misery,
痛苦
and illness together.
还有疾病
So she
所以小程对她来说
cares about Cheng more than anything.
格外地上心
Such care
但这种上心程度
may be good for a normal person.
对于正常人可能是好事
But for someone with a psychological illness,
但对于一个心理有疾病的人
it might not be the case.
也就未必了
That's why I'm worried about him.
所以我很担心他
It's still unknown for now,
CEO钱程的突然离职
whether the CEO's resignation
是否会对青霭品牌造成影响
will cause any impact on Qing'ai.
短时间内还不得而知
The third-generation designer
品牌第三代设计师
Mr. Dao Ruifeng told the public
刀锐锋先生对外表示
that the new CEO shall be announced soon.
新的CEO人选不日将对外官宣
William.
William
How is Qian Cheng doing?
钱程怎么样了
He said he's fine.
他嘴上说着没什么
That he's doing great.
一切都好
But I know
但我知道
he was only comforting me.
他在安慰我
I went to that place.
我去了那个地方
It's basically a prison.
那简直是个监狱
A madhouse.
是个疯人院
I went there
我去了以后
and saw that the chairs and tables were nailed to the ground.
桌子椅子都是钉在地上的
And I saw two strong male nurses
进进出出还有两个膀大腰圆的
with him.
男护士跟着
How can I let him stay there?
我能让他待在那儿吗
Please calm down.
你冷静一点
I have something to discuss with you.
我有事情要跟你商量
What is it?
你说吧 什么事
I caused all of this.
这个事情是因我而起
I'm thinking if I could speak to Peng Zichun.
我想去找找彭梓春
What's the point?
你找他干嘛呀
His family is unreasonable.
他们家人死咬着不放
Peng Zichun would only take advantage of you.
你去了只能让那个王八蛋占便宜
William, listen to me.
William听我说
I came back with the purpose of
我这次回来呢
taking Qian Cheng to the US to have him treated.
本来打算带钱程去美国治病的
I told him already.
我也跟他说了
He promised that he'd think about it.
他答应我考虑一下
If it weren't for the accident,
要不是这次意外
we'd be in the US by now.
我俩可能已经在美国了
He wants to go to the States with you?
他要跟你去美国啊
He didn't tell me about it.
他没跟我说
Maybe
他可能
he hasn't decided
还没有想好
how to break it to you.
该怎么跟你说吧
Anyway,
反正
I have made up my mind.
我已经下定决心了
No matter what happens,
不管发生什么事
I'll be with him through thick and thin.
我都和他风雨共担
William.
William
Because of their fight,
因为这次的事情
my family wants me to return to the US.
家里面要送我回美国
So before I leave,
所以我想走之前
I'd like to try one more time for Qian Cheng.
为钱程再努力一次
Peng Zichun will take advantage of you.
彭梓春会趁机占便宜的
But my family has influence, too.
可是我家里不是没有人啊
He can't do anything about me.
他不能把我怎么样
How about
要不
you help me ask Xue Wanwan?
你帮我去问问薛晚晚
Xue Zaozao must know
彭梓春住在哪个医院
which hospital Peng Zichun is in.
薛早早一定知道
If the Peng family knows you're going to beg for Qian Cheng,
彭家要是知道你为钱程求情
they'll be mad at you.
肯定会迁怒于你
If you do this,
你要是这么去了
Qian will be worried.
老钱肯定不放心
How about
要不
you going with me?
你陪我去
You wait for me outside.
你在外面等我
There are nurses.
那边有护士
There won't be any danger.
也不会有什么危险
I'll go with you.
我陪你去
Thank you, William.
谢谢William
No need to thank me.
谢什么呀
Qian Cheng's my best mate.
钱程是我最好的兄弟
I'll go.
去就去呗
I never expected him to be in your hospital.
我没想到这家伙住你们医院了
Yeah.
那当然
I told you
我早说了
that our orthopedics department is first-class nationwide.
我们医院的骨科是全国有名的
But I just asked.
不过我刚刚问了
Only some parts of his bones were broken.
他是局部骨折
He can dine without any problems.
吃喝什么都没问题
My brother said
我哥说
Peng Zichun asked to see Ye Lai as soon as he woke up.
彭梓春一醒就嚷着要见叶莱
Why did you cut in?
这里有你什么事
He's like a madman.
跟个神经病似的
Ye Lai,
叶莱
your visit
没准你来了
might just turn things around.
真能管用
You're like a mad person
你每次嚷嚷着要见
every time you ask to see William.
William的时候也像神经病
It's about visiting hours.
探视时间差不多到了
Ye Lai will follow me in first.
一会儿叶莱先跟我进去
Because of the registration policy,
因为要登记
you guys wait here.
所以你俩等一下
I'll go talk to the doctor, okay?
我去跟医生沟通一下 好吧
- Okay. - Let's go.
好 走吧
Can I
我
talk to you about something?
有件事要跟你商量
Can you not
你能不能不要
look at me like a creep?
像个痴汉一样的看着我
You're scaring me.
怪吓人的
I joined Cheng Weilan's volunteer association.
我加入程蔚蓝的志愿者协会了
Organ donation?
器官捐赠
I'll do good things later.
我以后要多多做善事
Am I brilliant?
我是不是很棒
You aren't some kind of artist in trouble.
你也不是什么翻车艺人
There's no need for you to clear your name through charity.
没必要拿这种公益洗白自己
You're unhappy?
你不高兴啊
No.
我没不高兴
I never yelled at you.
我以前从来没有凶过你
But after the incident,
但今天发生这样的事情
my best mate is in a prison-like hospital,
我最好的兄弟折进去了
and my own family is in a mess.
我自己的家族也乱一团
Can you please behave?
我拜托你能不能稍微乖一点
Don't cause more troubles for me.
不要再烦我了
Please.
好吗
It's okay that you like Cheng Weilan.
你喜欢程蔚蓝没关系
I'll be better and better,
我也会像她一样
just like her.
我会越来越棒的
But liking someone
但喜不喜欢
doesn't mean that they have to be perfect.
跟棒不棒没关系
Dao Ruifeng!
刀锐锋
I...
我
Brother!
哥
What are you doing?
你干吗
What?
干吗
-What are you doing? -Let's go.
你干吗啊你
Stop it.
别打了
It's a fight between my brother and my boyfriend.
我哥和我男朋友打架
It has nothing to do with you.
有你们什么事
I'll kick your butt if you take one step closer.
上来我揍你们
Shoo.
走走走
William, get him.
William加油
You ingrate sister!
你个没出息的死丫头
Brother, do your best, too.
哥 你也加油
The Xue family can't lose.
我们薛家不能输
Shut up, Xue Wanwan!
你闭嘴 薛晚晚
My dear, protect your face.
亲爱的 你护着点脸
Shut up!
你闭嘴
Why did you get yourself involved?
谁让你凑热闹的
Qian Cheng hit Peng Zichun.
钱程打了彭梓春
You fought Xue Zaozao.
你倒打了薛早早
You are good brothers, aren't you?
你们真是一对好兄弟呀
Grandmother.
奶奶
He hit me first.
他先动手的
He's the one in the hospital,
现在住院的是他
not you.
不是你
You're supposed to safeguard Young Master.
你是守护少爷
I don't even blame you for your dereliction of duty,
工作不认真也就罢了
but what about Qian Cheng?
你对得起钱程吗
It's been ten years.
这十多年来
The Qian family entrusted him with you
钱家把他交给了你
because they trust you and us.
是对你 跟对我们的信任
How can you face your friend?
你怎么对得起你的好朋友的
Grandmother.
奶奶
Qian Cheng hurt him badly
钱程在KTV
at the KTV?
把他打成重伤
He's amazing.
这么厉害
I can hardly believe it.
我都想不通
What is so unbelievable?
你有什么想不通的
Would all the customers and waiters
KTV那么多的客人跟服务员
make the same mistake?
还有看错的
Could it be a made-up story?
还有假
Mother.
母亲
Calm down.
你先不要激动
Calm down, please.
先不要激动啊
C-Come here.
过 过来
The Qian family aren't fools.
钱家也不是吃素的
If there
这个事情
is an inside story,
如果真的有内情
they will certainly find it out.
他们一定能查出原因的
But what I didn't understand
我倒纳闷
was why you went along with Ye Lai
这个叶莱去找彭梓春
to meet Peng Zichun?
你跟着干吗去
I...
我
I-I'm worried about her.
我 我这不是担心她嘛
Xue Zaozao came up to me and hit me for no reason,
薛早早把我拎起来就一顿揍
so I...
所以我
Enough! Stop justifying yourself!
行了 你别辩解了
I've booked you an air ticket to France today.
我已经定了今天你飞法国的机票
Your parents are expecting you at the airport.
你的父母在机场等你
Grandmother,
奶奶
I can't leave right now.
现在我不能走
You, too, know you can't leave at this time, huh?
你也知道这个时候不能走啊
Then why did you cause troubles?
那你干吗惹麻烦
Be good.
听话啊
The longer you stay here,
你现在只要在这儿待着
the bigger the mess you'll cause.
就会把事情越搞越乱
Listen to your uncle.
听二叔的
Go home and stay with your parents.
回家 陪爸妈待两天
When we sort it out,
等我们把事情处理完了
you can come back.
你再回来
Everything will remain the same.
一样的
Uncle, I can't leave!
二叔我不能走
How can I leave Qian Cheng behind?
我怎么会丢下钱程一个人呢
What are you talking about?
胡闹吗
You can't leave him behind?
你不丢下他
What? Are you going to be hospitalized with him?
你还能进去陪他去
Look at your injury.
你看看这伤的
It breaks my heart.
你这让二叔怪心疼的
Listen to me. Go home.
听二叔的话 回去吧
You always wanted to go home, right?
你不是一直想回去吗
Sooner rather than later, right?
早走晚走都是走
Now, you...
你现在
No!
我不行
Go home and get some rest.
回去好好休息一下
Grandmother!
奶奶
Go home and write your stories.
回去当两天作者
Go, go, go.
去吧去吧去吧
Go.
去吧
You'll be late for the flight.
飞机快晚点了
The top priority now
现在最要紧的
is the management of Qing'ai.
是青霭的管理问题
The CEO resigned abruptly.
CEO毫无征兆地辞职
William, the designer,
William这个设计师
returns to France all of a sudden.
又突然间回国
All the work
接下来 所有的工作
needs to be rearranged.
都要重新安排啊
Mr. Liu can do some of it.
刘总可以承担一部分的工作
As for the rest,
剩下的
I'll deal with them myself.
我亲自处理
You?
您亲自处理
It's been decades.
这几十年来
There had never been a scenario where
青霭从来没有过
a CEO of Qing'ai needed compulsory treatment.
CEO被强迫治疗的情况
Only by handling things myself
只有我亲自处理
can the situation stay under control.
才能控制局势
I think
我想
neither the Peng family nor the Xue family will let it slide.
彭家 薛家不会善罢甘休的
Prepare for upcoming turmoils.
等着血雨腥风的日子吧
William.
William
I, William, have a great reputation since ever.
我William一世英名
But now only one person is here to see me off?
就你一个人送我
Jin Xiaoyu said
金小鱼说
you only informed me.
你只通知了我一个人
Who else are you expecting?
你还想让谁来
Right.
也是啊
Umm...
那什么
Come closer.
你过来点
What?
怎么了
I'm leaving.
我这都要走了
Kiss me goodbye.
吻别一下
Have you grown tired of your brain?
你是不是脑子不想要了
I'll donate it on your behalf.
不想要帮你捐了
I was...
我不
I was only joking.
我这不是跟你开玩笑的吗
But think about it.
你考虑一下
Lan,
蓝蓝
I sincerely want to be with you. Please...
我是真心实意地追求 你
Think about it.
考虑一下
I've prepared what you asked for.
你要的东西我都准备好了
Also, tell Qian
还有 告诉老钱
that I'll be back for him.
我一定会回来陪他的
That I won't leave him behind.
不会丢下他
I'm off.
那我走了
Take care.
那你保重啊
Bye-bye.
拜拜
My...
我
My stomach.
肚子有点疼
I need to go to the bathroom.
我上个厕所
Give me a minute.
等我一下